一切都还好吗
It's all going on, isn't it?
西奥去哪了
Where's Theo?
去参加了个关于软体动物的会议
Away at a conference... about molluscs.
都没人和我一起去收集屎壳郎了
No-one else will collect dung beetles with me.
那倒不奇怪 对吧
That's hardly surprising, isn't it?
他们就是粪便做成的虫子
I mean they're beetles made of dung.
它们不是由粪便做的 而是靠这个活
They're not made of dung. They live on dung.
它们把粪便分开后 滚成球
They cut it, then they roll it
然后埋起来
and they bury it.
要是你爸爸在这里就好了
If only your father were here.
- 他对大自然感兴趣么 - 不
- Was he interested in nature? - No.
你为什么不去钓鱼呢
Why don't you go fishing?
老实说 这样我们就可以吃鱼了
To be honest, we could do with the fish.
好了 好了 谢谢你们送我回家
Yeah, yeah. Thanks for walking me home.
你们太贴心了 但是我要结婚了
You're so sweet but I'm getting married.
我妈妈撮合的 我未婚夫在船厂工作
My mother's making me. He's in shipping.
干得不错
Well done.
自那上一个后
I couldn't take any more
我再也不能忍受你恋爱的烦恼了
of your romantic upsets after the last one.
不 我还在找呢 我就是不喜欢他们
Oh, no, I'm still looking. I just don't really fancy them.
我应该去港口看看
I might try the harbour.
马戈 你该去找个工作
Margo, you need a job.
为什么是我 拉里和莱斯利呢
Why me? What about Larry and Leslie?
我有工作
I have a job!
那可不是工作
It's not a job.
- 就是装样子 - 闭嘴 莱斯利
- It's showing off. - Shut up, Leslie!
她快结婚了 未婚夫在船厂工作
She's getting married. Someone in shipping.
你觉得这不是工作吗
You don't think this is work?
六个月的血和汗还有...
This is six months of blood and sweat and...
其他液体我就不说了
other fluids I won't go into.
是的 我知道 干得好 亲爱的
Yes, I know. Well done, dear.
粗糙的双手搭成帐篷形 做着礼拜
Gnarled were the hands, tented in worship.
湿透的衣服紧贴着她 就像灰白棚架上的苔藓
The sodden coat clumped round her like moss on grizzled trellis.
写得真好 但别给我说内容了
Oh, is lovely, darling. Don't spoil it for me though.
太好了 有吃的
Thank God, food.
不 这个是给亚历克西娅的
Uh-uh. It's for Alexia.
是给我们两个月纪念日准备的
It's our two-month anniversary.
贴心的男孩
Oh, sweet boy.
他是最好的孩子
He is best child.
在英格兰
You see, back in England,
我们对待孩子都尽量公平 鲁格勒斯雅
we try not to have favourites, Lugaretzia.
他是最好的孩子
He is best child.
但是这对他来说是好事
But it is nice for him.
我们都需要爱 他有亚历克西娅了
We all need love. He has Alexia.
拉里 在英格兰你有南希
Larry, you have Nancy back in England.
- 那你有... - 好吧 拉里
- And you have...? - All right, Larry.
我知道你想说什么
I know what you're going to say.
谢谢 我能照顾我自己
Thank you, I can look after myself.
给亚历克西娅的
For Alexia.
德雷尔一家 第一季 第三集
来啊 做点什么
Go on, then. Do something.
你好 德雷尔小姐
Hello, Miss Durrells.
你好 斯皮罗斯
Hello, Spiro.
- 你想搭车吗 - 不 我没事 谢谢你
- You want a lift? - No, no, I'm fine, thank you.
- 上车吧 - 不不不 我没事
- I'll give you a lift. - No, no. No, I'm fine.
不 上车吧
No, I'll give you a lift.
好极了
Bravo!
你好
Hello.
英国人
English?
是的 我叫格里
Yes. Gerry.
克斯提
Kostis.
你为什么要躲着我
Why were you hiding from me?
没有 我只是... 躲太阳
No, I was just... getting some shade.
不 你在躲我
No, you were hiding.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
麻烦进城就行 斯皮罗斯
Um, just into town, please, Spiro.
说吧 你要去哪里
Come on, where you going?
去斯文那里
To Sven's house.
- 你为什么要去那里 - 去问他个问题
- Why you going there? - To ask him a question.
问我啊 我是万事通
Ask me. I know everything.
- 他是瑞典人 - 他救了拉里一命
- He's a Swede. - He saved Larry's life.
再说 瑞典人又怎么了
What's the matter with the Swedes, anyway?
太懒了 连个像英国和
Too lazy to make an empire
希腊一样的国家都建不成
like the British and the Greeks. Much too lazy.
鹭
Erodios.
白鹭
Egret.
你好 斯文
Hello, Sven.
路易莎
Louisa.
关于昨天要付拉里的手术费 我想道个歉
I wanted to apologise for offering to pay for Larry's operation.
英国人都很绅士
You were just being British.
你们不喜欢欠别人人情
You don't like being in anyone's debt.
难道和你们瑞典人差这么多吗
Are you so different in Sweden?
我不知道 可我每年都少点瑞典人气息
I don't know. I'm getting less Swedish every year.
可能降到38%了吧
I think I'm down to 38%.
但是我喜欢希腊人 他们诚实
But I like the Greeks, their honesty.
我倒想沾点希腊人的气息
Mm. I wouldn't mind a bit of Greek in me.
别弹了
Oh, stop it.
你喜欢手风琴吗
Do you like the accordion?
不怎么喜欢
Um, no, not really.
现在不怎么喜欢诚实了吧
Not so fond of honesty now?
- 每个人都喜欢手风琴 - 好吧...
- Everybody likes the accordion. - Well...
我想问问你
Um, I was wondering if
知不知道怎么收橄榄的事情
you knew anything about olive harvesting...
你到底不喜欢手风琴什么地方
What exactly is it you don't like?
我...
Mm. I...
音色 这个看起来像...
The sound, the way it looks like a little...
给侏儒拉的钢琴 我...
piano for dwarves. I...
那你更喜欢布祖基琴吗
You prefer the bouzouki,
那种看上去给傻子弹的小竖琴
which is like a tiny harp for... idiots?
我有一些动物
I have some animals.
我喜欢动物 还有... 他们需要喂养
I like animals and... they need feeding...
- 所以我得回家了 - 过来
- so I have to go home now. - Come. Ela.
好吧
Oh, dear.
你想和阿勒克罗打个招呼吗
You want to say hello to Alecko?
什么情况
What's going on?
这是谁
Who's this?
- 斯特拉托斯 - 你好啊
- Stratos. - Yassas.
他是我以前的男朋友
He is my old boyfriend.
然后呢
All right.
和我的新男朋友
And my new boyfriend.
你的自行车真娘
Your bicycle is for a girl.
这个是给亚历克西娅的礼物
It's a present... for Alexia.
不 你不能给她了
No, you cannot give it to her.
那好啊 我会为她和你打一场
All right then, I'll fight you for her.
你看 亚历克西娅不想这样
You see, Alexia doesn't want that.
可以啊 如果你想打的话
Well, OK, if you want.
不 我不...
No, I don't...
好吧 好吧 我们来决斗
Fine. Fine, let's have a duel.
- 什么珍珠 - 用枪决斗
- A jewel? - A duel, with guns.
- 那太危险了 - 危险且愚蠢
- That's dangerous. - Dangerous. And silly.
走吧 走
Go away. Go!
不
Oh, no.
亲爱的 怎么了
Darling, what's the matter?
我和亚历克西娅分手了
I had to end it with Alexia.
莱斯利 对不起
Oh. Leslie, I'm so sorry.
她以前的男朋友回来了
Her old boyfriend came back.
- 这太让人心烦了 - 我讨厌她
- It's so upsetting. - I hate her.
别这样
Well, don't.
- 是挺讨厌的 - 她是...
- Actually do. - She was...
- 我知道我什么都做不好 - 不会啊
- I know I'm not good at anything. - You are.
我不好 我不像拉里那么聪明
I'm not. I'm not clever like Larry
像格里那么有魅力 或者...
or charming like Gerry or...
不管马戈有什么好的 我都差
whatever Margo is.
- 她... - 除了枪以外
- Well, she's... - Apart from my guns,
她是我遇见过的最美好之物
she was the first good thing that ever happened to me.
还有你的家庭呢
Well, there's your family.
看看这个 我哭都哭不好
Look at this. I can't even cry nicely.
他好漂亮 对吧 阿勒克罗
He's beautiful. Aren't you, Alecko?
- 漂亮 - 送你了
- You are. - For you.
- 你带他走吧 - 真的吗
- You take him. - Really?
你的... 家里人...
And your er... family...
会喜欢他吗
will like him?
家庭... 就像...
Family... is like er...
健康一样
good health.
只当你丢失了才会挂念
You miss it only when it is gone.
你需要给他喂鱼
You will need fish for him.
明天过来 我们要捕很多鱼
Come back tomorrow, we catch a lot.
我会的
I will.
你确定不要他了吗
Sure you don't want him?
在我住的地方很难养他
It is hard to keep him where I live.
为什么 你家里人不喜欢他吗
Why? Do your family not like him?
除了周末 我都是住在那个岛上
Er... except for weekends I live on that island.
监狱岛吗
The prison island?
你在那里工作吗
Do you work there?
不
No.
所以你是犯人
So you're a convict.
这肯定有诀窍的 去问问鲁格勒斯雅怎么做的
I'm sure there's a knack. Ask Lugaretzia how it's done.
她说橄榄花粉会让她的脸过敏
She says the olive pollen irritates her face.
她的脸看起来一直像在过敏
Her face always looks irritated.
那花粉会让她的脸更过敏
Well, it makes it more irritated.
能帮帮我吗
Will you help me?
- 我在工作 - 我在找工作
- I'm working. - Looking for a job.
- 你在干什么 - 推你一把 给你点动力
- What are you doing? - I am putting a rocket up your backside.
去推莱斯利啊
Well, put it up Leslie's.
你女朋友的事 我深表遗憾 小莱
Sorry to hear about your girlfriend, Les.
我也是
Me too.
我也... 非常遗憾
Me too... very much.
- 亲爱的 莱斯利 你去哪 - 去打猎
- Darling. Leslie. Where are you going? - Shooting.
但... 答应我...
But... promise me...
你不会去杀了亚历克西娅或她的...
promise me you won't shoot Alexia or her...
新朋友
new friend.
当然不会 你需要晚饭 不是吗
Of course I won't. You want supper, don't you?
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
在认识你们父亲之前 我拒绝了许多小伙子
Before I met your father I turned down lots of young men.
他们都是笑一笑就过去了
They laughed about it afterwards.
或许他们不是真想和你约会
Maybe they didn't really want to go out with you.
您知道有什么工作适合马戈吗
Do you know anyone who might have work for Margo?
我不知道从哪开始
I don't know where to start.
你对什么样的工作感兴趣
Well, what kind of job are you interested in?
我不知道 与时尚... 或者美食相关吧
I don't know. Something to do with fashion... or posh food.
你是把科孚和巴黎弄混了吧
I think you're muddling Corfu up with Paris.
您能不能留下她
Do you think you might have something for her,
给您或者配崔迪斯医生帮忙
helping you and Dr. Petridis?
可能不行 你有什么经验吗
Not really. Do you have any experience?
没有 没什么...
No, not ...
没有 但她喜欢排解他人痛苦
No, but she's always loved alleviating suffering.
不是吗 亲爱的
Haven't you, darling?
你知道的 那次... 你...
You know, that... that time... when you...
我什么
What?
请拜托给她份工作就好
Please give her a bloody job.
我们应该可以让她做些基本的辅助工作
I suppose we could use some general help.
- 跑腿 清理之类的 - 太好了
- You know, errands, tidying. - That's wonderful.
而且可能很快就会变成真正的护士
And in time that might become actual nursing.
之后还会变成马戈医生
Dr Margo will see you now.
- 会很有趣的 - 我们先别考虑那么远
- You know, that might be fun. - Let's not jump ahead.
我们不会让你
We won't be asking you to
去切阑尾的 那个归斯文管
cut out an appendix. We've got Sven for that.
你去见过他了吗
Have you seen him at all?
不... 我... 并没有去
No, I... Um, no, I don't think I have.
- 马戈 你希腊语说得如何 - 我...
- Margo, how's your Greek? - I'm ...
说得很好 她学得非常快
Oh, it's very good. She's incredibly quick.
事实证明 马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人
It turns out the Countess
的确得了不治之症
Mavrodaki does have an incurable disease.
- 亲爱的 - 臆想症
- Darling. - Hypochondria.
她还有一个巨大的...
She also has an enormous...
路易莎来了
Louisa's here.
别墅
villa.
- 您好 - 马戈要来工作一周
- Hello. - Margo is going to come and work here for a week.
或许... 接着一直留下来
And then perhaps... permanently.
很好 你什么时候能开始上班
Excellent. When can you start?
- 越快越好 - 秋天再说
- As soon as possible. - In the autumn?
闭嘴
Shut your face.
- 你这是干什么 不行 - 什么
- What are you doing? No. - What?
你不能把信天翁带回家来
You can't bring an albatross home.
这是海鸥
It's a gull.
这是信天翁 看看它的块头
It's an Albatross. Look at size of it.
它在磨牙呢
It's gnashing its teeth.
- 它们没有牙 - 那它也是在嚼东西
- They haven't got teeth. - It's gnashing something.
是"他" 而且他叫阿勒克罗
It's a he, and he's called Alecko.
我不信给动物取名那一套
I don't believe in naming animals.
拟人是笨蛋做的事
Anthropomorphism is for halfwits.
还是算了
Perhaps not.
我会再做一个笼子
I'll build another cage.
它们到处拉屎撒尿
They're pissing and crapping.
管管它们
Stop them.
我将救死扶伤
I'll be healing the sick and the lame.
此乃吾之使命
It's a calling.
你只是个打杂的 不是护士
You'll be a dogsbody, not a nurse.
现代护理学创立人
我可比佛罗伦斯·南丁格尔好看多了
I'm a damn sight prettier than Florence Nightingale.
我敢说 在她的家人把她累垮之前
I'm sure she was ravishing
她还是很美的
before her family wore her down.
回来了 莱斯利
Oh, hello, Leslie.
看来你非常生气啊 是吗
Oh, you were really angry, weren't you?
- 外面为什么有只信天翁 - 谢谢
- Why is there an albatross outside? - Thank you.
是 我已经说过格里了
Yes, I've already told Gerry off.
一个与他同样喜爱生物的朋友
He was given to him by Kostis,
克斯提 送给他的
who's clearly as keen on creatures as Gerry,
所以他们是好朋友
so he's a nice friend for him.
他为什么不自己养那只信天翁
Why can't he look after the albatross?
那不是信天翁
It's not an albatross.
他不能养 因为除了周末
And he can't because during the week
其他时间他要蹲监狱
he's in jail.
什么
What?
你思想真开放啊
Mm. How open-minded are you?
- 他为什么进的监狱 - 他不想说
- Why is he in jail? - He didn't want to say.
你永远不会明白这些科孚人...
You never know these Corfiots ...
什么都干得出来
capable of anything.
你女朋友另觅高枝 不代表所有人都是坏人
Everyone isn't evil just because your girlfriend got a better offer.
你再说一遍
Say that again and I'll
我就烧了你正在写的那本书
burn the book you're writing.
你们两个能不能别吵了
Would you stop squabbling?
格里...
Gerry...
好的 我明天再去问问克斯提
All right, I'll ask Kostis again tomorrow.
不 你明天不能去
No, you're not going again tomorrow.
- 为什么 - 因为他可能是个杀人犯
- Why not? - Because he could be a murderer.
既然都让他周末出来了
He can't do anything that bad
- 就不可能有多坏 - 没错
- if they let him out at weekends. - Exactly.
这可不一定 在科孚 杀人会被判三年
Don't be so sure. In Corfu you get three years for murder
而炸鱼会被判五年
and five years if you're caught dynamiting fish.
我不在乎他做过什么 他很和善
I don't care what Kostis did. He's friendly and kind.
但我很在乎
Well I do care.
因为我要对你负责 还要确保你的安全
Cause I'm responsible for you and it is my job to keep you safe.
那我们为什么要搬家
Why did you bring us here then?
汉普郡比这要安全无数倍
It's a million times less safe than Hampshire.
如果你非得要和犯人一起钓鱼 那当然不安全
Well, it is if you insist on going fishing with convicts.
回答你的问题
And since you ask,
我把大家带到这里是为了...
I brought us here because...
我想让大家开心
because I wanted us to be happy.
慢点 吃早餐不要狼吞虎咽
Slow down. Don't wolf your breakfast.
是不是很好吃
Is it nice?
格里
Oh, Gerry.
我又做错了什么
What have I done wrong now?
去见你的朋友克斯提吧
Go and see your friend Kostis.
谢谢你 妈妈
Thank you, Mum.
你比我们都有责任心 我应该更信任你的
You're more responsible than all of us. I should trust you more.
我这不叫反复无常 叫善于变通
I'm not being inconsistent, I'm being flexible.
- 很好 - 但你得带个人一起去
- Good. - But you will have to take someone with you.
- 我是女生 - 不行 不行 我很忙
- I'm a girl. - No, no, no. I'm busy.
"你好 你叫什么名字"
"Oh, hello. So, what's your name?"
"劈腿的女友 你呢"
"Cheating girlfriend, what's yours?"
"莱斯利 容易受骗的莱斯利
"Leslie. Leslie Gullible.
很高兴见到你"
Lovely to meet you."
- 格里 - 你好
- Gerry. - Hello.
- 他是谁 - 我哥哥 莱斯利
- Who is he? - My brother Leslie.
他为什么带着枪
Why he has gun?
我另外一个哥哥拉里说 这是阴茎替代物
My other brother Larry says it's a penis substitute.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你看到没
Did you see that?
- 拉里 - 我灵感来了 停不下来
- Larry. - I mustn't stop, I'm in the mood.
帮我劝劝莱斯利
Help me with Leslie.
他没事的 时间是治愈良药
He's fine. Time is a big healer,
还意味着很多次的手淫
and plenty of so-called self-abuse.
这真是成年人干的事啊
Well, that's very mature.
帮帮你弟弟 做一个伙伴劝劝他
Help your brother. Be a pal to him.
我们性格差别太大了
We're so different.
好吧 我会带他进城转转
All right. I'll take him into town.
明天穿这身去工作 怎么样
For work tomorrow. What do you think?
不行 马戈
No, Margo.
不过很高兴看你算是会做衣服了
Still, good to see you dressmaking, sort of.
有客人来了
There's a guest.
给
Here.
妈妈 你看 多漂亮的水龟啊
Mum, look, the most amazing terrapin.
- 是啊 - 我叫它"老扑腾"
- Oh, yes. - I'm calling him Old Plop.
因为...
Because...?
因为他很老... 而且总扑腾
He's old and... he goes plop.
你好 我是德雷尔太太
Hello. I'm Mrs. Durrell.
我是克斯提
Kostis.
我们要去给龟修一个池塘
We're going to build a pond for it.
你还好吗... 老伙计
All right there... my old matey?
他需要朋友
He needs friends.
我听说你在服刑
I hear you're in prison.
是的
Yes.
多少年
For how many years?
- 三年 - 三年
- Er, three years. - Three years.
那么... 监狱如何
And... how is prison?
监狱就是监狱
It is a prison, uh?
监狱就是监狱 当然
It is a prison, of course.
我能否问问你为何入狱
May I ask how you came to be there?
- 我的英语... - 因为
- My English... - Because you see,
我必须得确定格里和你在一起是安全的
I have to know that Gerry is safe with you.
格里 下周末再见
Gerry. Until the next weekend.
他为什么走了 你跟他说了什么
Why's he gone? What did you say?
我认为你不该见他
I don't think you should see him.
我跟他说了下周末见就下周末见
I promised him I'd see him next weekend and I am going to.
大多数病人是因为小病来找我们的
Most patients come to us with minor ailments.
就像弗洛伦斯·南丁格尔说的那样
As Florence Nightingale said,
"别弄出人命就行"
"Just don't kill anybody."
我是转述
I'm paraphrasing.
你不需要接触任何医疗相关的东西
Mm. You won't be doing anything medical
但恐怕会见到一些吓人的场面
but there will be a few gruesome sights, I'm afraid.
- 我已经做好准备了 - 好女孩
- Oh, I've prepared myself for that. - Good girl.
天哪 我要吐了
Oh, God, I'm going to be sick.
- 你好 斯皮罗斯 - 你好 德雷尔女士
- Hello, Spiro. - Hello, Miss Durrells.
- 你要去哪 - 不 我只想问个问题
- Where you want to go? - No, I just have a question.
你认识一个叫克斯提的吗 他关在维托监狱
Do you a man called Kosti? He's in Vito Jail.
对 就是他
Oh, yes. Him.
他杀了他的妻子
He murdered his wife.
为什么要问他
Why you ask?
他周末的时候被放出来了
He's been let out at the
而且还和格里一起钓鱼
weekends and he's been fishing with Gerry.
你应该马上阻止他们
You should stop this right now.
我记得 他有一个儿子 但被带走了
I remember, he has a son who was taken from him
和离他很远的祖父母一起生活
and lives far away with his grandparents.
这也是他喜欢和格里在一起的原因
That's why he likes to be with Gerry perhaps.
也是他不安全的原因
And why he's not very safe.
英国小说家 戏剧家
萨默塞特·毛姆怎么样 他最近有点惨
What about Somerset Maugham, eh? He's a bit shit these days.
谁
Wh-Who?
那个作家 萨默塞特
The writer, Somerset...
算了
Never mind.
韦伯利公司正考虑
Webley's are thinking of
修改第二代步枪的准星
modifying the sights on the Mark II rifle.
请包扎一下 马戈
Dressing, please, Margo.
我要晕了
I'm going to faint.
- 就一点血 - 别提血
- It's only a bit of blood. - Don't say blood.
在诊所不能说血
Don't say blood in a doctor's surgery?
所以 你现在不用看
So, now you won't have
所谓"恶心的东西"了
to see the 'yucky things', as you call them.
我们要让你做一些文书工作
We'll move you to paperwork.
太好了
Oh, fine.
我还不会讲希腊语 没关系吗
And not speaking Greek yet, will that be a problem?
- 你确定想在这工作吗 - 当然
- Are you sure you want to work here? - Oh, yes, yes.
妈妈会为我骄傲的
Mum's really proud of me.
她很少为我骄傲
That's quite rare, actually.
要不要再去别的诊室
Should I have another go
- 试试是否恶心头晕吗 - 不 待在这
- and try not to heave or faint? - No, stay here.
学学希腊语 急什么呢
Learn Greek. What's the hurry?
马戈的性格有些...
Margo's been...
我不是说她天生如此
I mean, I wouldn't say she's a natural.
她很难与那些
She's uneasy with what
- 她称作"厌恶的老人"相处 - 保佑她
- she calls "repulsive old people". - Bless her.
似乎超过四十岁都算了
Seems to be anyone over 40.
- 你还好吗 - 如果你有个儿子
- Are you all right? - If you had a son,
你会让他和一个
would you let him go fishing
可能是杀人犯的人一起钓鱼吗
with a convict who might be a murderer?
天哪 什么叫可能是
Gosh. Might be?
没错 有一个杀人犯
See, there's this murderer,
叫克斯提... 帕纳...
Kosti... er Pana...
不知道 无论如何 可能不是他
Oh, I don't know. Anyway, it might not be him.
- 克斯提是个常见的名字 - 我知道
- Kosti's a common name. - I know.
弗洛伦斯 我不知道怎么办
Oh, Florence, I don't know what to do.
问问斯文
Ask Sven.
他住在这儿很多年了
He's lived here for years and,
而且作为一个男人 非常...
as a man, very much so...
为什么每个人都喜欢斯文
Why is everyone so obsessed with Sven?
他就是个狡猾的瑞典人
He's just a tricky bloody Swede.
抱歉 我以为你们俩个很合得来
Excuse me, I just thought you two might get on.
很明显 并不好
Well, quite clearly we don't.
他有可能因为偷了一张邮政汇票而坐牢
He's most likely in jail for stealing a postal order.
蹲三年 就因为偷一张汇票
Three years for a postal order?
炸鱼还要判五年呢
Five years for dynamiting fish.
科孚有自己的规定
They have their own rules here.
他们不会让
They'll hardly let a
一个暴力的杀人犯外出钓鱼
violent murderer out to do a spot of angling.
你说得对 格里能感觉得到
Mm. You're right. You're right. And Gerry's very sensible.
- 他很擅长判断人的性格 - 格里
- He's a very good judge of character. - Gerry?
我们看过他跟老鼠聊天
Who we found chatting to a rat?
抱歉
Sorry.
我的儿子 他和你一样大
My son, he's the age of you.
我不能见他
I must not see him.
我三岁时 父亲去世了
My father died when I was three.
我对他只有一段记忆
I have only one memory of him.
我们俩
Both of us...
一起看池塘里的小金鱼
watching the goldfish in our pond.
小小的橙色鱼
You know, little orange fish?
- 干得好 - 谢谢你
- Oh, well done. - Thank you.
你是按日期还是按患者名字来排序的
Did you decide to go by date order or patient name?
患者的身高
Um, patient height.
- 身高 - 是的 因为这是
- Height? - Yes. Because it's the first
你表格的第一项 所以一定很重要
thing on your form, so it must be important.
个高的病例在这儿
Taller patients are up here.
所以根本不需要记名字 反正我总是忘记
So no need to remember names ... which I always forget anyway.
你只需要记住他们多高
You just need to remember how tall they are.
- 没错 - 这些文件呢
- Right. - What are these files?
这是上一位医生的
It's the last doctor's.
好像被警方叫去做协助案件的医学报告了
Seems to be medical reports on police cases he was called out on.
别管这些了
Just... just leave them.
而且先别碰其他的了
In fact, don't touch anything else.
科斯提·帕帕多珀
Kosti Papadopol...
在档案室干得不错 听说你按身高来排序
So, good work on the filing. In order of height, I hear.
我开始觉得这是个愚蠢的想法了
I'm beginning to think that might have been a stupid idea.
总之 现在是星期五的中午
Anyway, it's Friday afternoon,
给你这星期的工资
so there's your wages for the week.
- 听着 - 我知道不太好
- Look ... - I know this is horrible,
但我恐怕不能在这工作了
but I'm afraid I can't work here.
我不擅长整理档案 而且每个人都生着病
I'm not very good at filing and everyone's so unwell.
而且以后还会看到更多病人
And it's just going to go on and on and on.
格里
Gerry?
今天还好吗
So, did today go well?
当然 为什么不好
Of course. Why wouldn't it?
别生气了 我从诊所借来了这个
Don't be cross, but I borrowed this from the surgery.
我不擅长治病 但是个称职的侦探
I may not be good with the sick but I am a good sleuth.
你在说什么 马戈
What are you talking about, Margo?
这是个医生写的犯罪现场报告
It's a doctor's report from a crime scene.
我花了一天时间翻译它
I spent all day translating it.
英国著名侦探小说家
我就是希腊版的阿加莎·克里斯蒂
I'm like a Greek Agatha Christie.
阿加莎笔下一名女侦探 马普尔小姐（Marple） 此处是马戈用自己的名字和其名字拼接而取的名字
马普戈小姐
Miss Marpo.
你懂这个梗吗
Do you get it?
克斯提 帕帕... 帕帕先生
Mr. Kosti Pap... Pap...
妻子身上有多处刺伤
wife had many stab wounds.
残忍的殴打
Brutal beating?
山羊人在外面
Oh, um, the goat chap is outside.
- 什么 - 救了拉里一命的那个外国人
- What? - You know, the foreigner who saved Larry's life.
是的 多亏了他 山羊人
Yeah, thanks for that, goat chap.
- 打算开个动物园 - 他们都是格里的
- Starting a zoo? - Oh, they're Gerry's.
- 比起人他更喜欢动物 - 我和他一样
- He prefers animals to people. - I agree with him.
对 我和每个人一样都惊叹于蜘蛛网
Yes. I mean, I admire a spider's web as much as anyone,
但我还是更喜欢去圣保罗大教堂
but I still prefer St Paul's Cathedral.
男人真暴力
Men are so violent.
很抱歉我冒犯了你 就因为你不喜欢...
I'm sorry I took offence at your dislike of the...
很抱歉 我之前不喜欢你拉...
I'm sorry I didn't enjoy your playing of the er...
他们太礼貌了
It's all so polite.
去床上解决啊
Go to bed.
我们走吧
Hey, come on then.
带我去喝酒
Take me drinking.
你说你搞不定那些的橄榄
You said you have trouble with your olives.
是的
Yes.
用网
Nets.
这是一个非常希腊式的解决方法
It's a very Greek solution.
把网铺好 然后你等就可以了
Just leave the nets. You wait.
思考一下人生
Contemplate existence.
时不时抖一下
Then you occasionally collect.
再等一下
Then you wait some more.
我和弗洛伦斯·配崔迪斯聊过了
I talked to Florence Petridis.
她告诉我你在担心一个罪犯
She told me you were worried about a criminal.
- 我能帮上忙吗 - 不用了
- Can I help? - No.
真的不用了
No, really.
- 你这不会是英国人的绅士吧 - 不是
- You're not just being British? - Oh, no.
我身上的英国气息变少了
I get less British by the day.
只剩下89%了
I'm down to 89%.
好吧 你知道他们这里有一句话
Well, you know what they say around here.
能告诉我这句话什么意思吗
Remind me what they mean?
"你知道我在哪里"
"You know where I am."
格里
Gerry?
格里去哪里了
Where's Gerry?
我听到他骑着自行车出去了
I think I heard him leave on the bike.
克斯提
Kosti.
格里 格里
Gerry? Gerry!
- 去叫莱斯利和拉里 - 他们出去了
- Get Leslie and Larry. - They've gone out.
格里
Gerry!
够了 别苦着一张脸了
Enough. No more moping.
我会给你找个新女友的
We'll find you a new girlfriend.
只有一个亚历克西娅
There's only one Alexia.
那可不太可能
I doubt that, actually.
- 亚历克西娅 - 啊
- Alexia? - Nai?
看到了吗
Hm. See?
你只是运气好
Lucky guess.
- 而且她长得像马 - 才不是
- And she looks like a horse. - No, she doesn't.
她怎么样 太美了
What about her? Sensational.
- 不 她长得像马 - 你才像马
- No, she looks like a horse. - You look like a horse.
我去把她拿下
I'll bring her over.
你好
Hello.
我是劳伦斯·德雷尔
I'm Lawrence Durrell.
我是一名作家
I'm an author.
格里
Gerry!
你是本地人吗
And are you local?
你的鼻子遗传了谁的 真美
Where did you get that nose? It's beautiful.
父母吧 你真... 坏
My parents? You are... a bad boy.
那听上去很可疑...
That sounds suspiciously like...
你好 我是莱斯利·德雷尔
Hello. I'm Leslie Durrell.
Hello. Leslie Durrell.
虽然我不在乎 但你是谁
I don't care, but who are you?
- 好 - 我们回家吧
- Good. - Let's go home.
- 不要 - 我可以给你一点恋爱的建议吗
- No. - Can I give you advice about women?
- 不可以 - 不要太有戒心
- No. - Don't be defensive.
你是一个好男人 诚实和脆弱就好
You're a decent chap. Just be honest and vulnerable.
- 你个傻逼 - 我觉得你喝够了
- Shove it up your arse. - I think you've had enough.
我这是借酒消愁
Mm. Well, I'm drinking to forget.
- 还有借吃消愁 - 好吧
- And eating to forget. Mm. - Right.
快跑
Go, go!
带去警察局
To the police station.
这其中有误会
There's been a misunderstanding here.
他在偷马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人的东西
He was stealing from the Countess Mavrodaki.
你们... 快走吧
You ... leave.
莱斯利
Leslie.
还在为我伤心吗
Still being so sad about me?
莱斯利
Leslie.
傻 太傻了
Stupid, stupid boy.
格里 你应该告诉我
Gerry, You should have told me
- 你去哪里的 - 要说了你肯定不让我去
- where you were going. - You wouldn't have let me go.
你和克斯提在偷东西
You and Kosti were stealing.
克斯提只是一片好意
Kosti was being kind.
马戈给我看了一份警察局里的医疗档案 格里
Margo showed me a police medical file, Gerry.
他捅了他的妻子 玛利亚
He stabbed his wife, Maria,
十六刀 然后把她扔进海里
16 times and then he threw her in the sea.
- 克斯提的妻子叫伊欧利亚 - 什么
- Kosti's wife was called Ioulia. - What?
她叫玛利亚·帕帕多普洛斯
It's Maria Papadopoulos.
是伊欧利亚·潘欧帕罗斯
Ioulia Panoupolos.
你连他的名字都没读对 根本不了解他
You don't even know his name properly or anything about him.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
那他是另外一个克斯提
So he's a different Kosti.
她埋在山谷的墓园里
She's buried in the cemetery in the valley.
克斯提经常去她的坟墓 打扫得干净体面
Kosti visits her grave all the time and keeps it beautiful.
现在他被抓了 以后就别想出狱了
Now they'll arrest him and he'll never get out of prison.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
我早上告诉你
I'll tell you in the morning.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
他们早上会告诉你的
They'll tell you... in the morning.
什么样的警察局早上九点才开门
What sort of police station opens at nine o'clock in the morning?
谢谢
Thank you.
你先回家 我待会再跟你说
You go home. I'll speak to you later.
莱斯利
Leslie.
请放了克斯提吧
Please release Kosti.
他必须得回到岛上
He must go back to the island.
他只是想帮我儿子
He was just trying to help my son.
如果他再陷入什么麻烦
If he gets in any more trouble
他们会把他关上好几年的
they'll lock him away for years.
你知道这里的规矩
You understand the system. Hooray.
德雷尔小姐
Miss Durrells?
德雷尔小姐 我听说了事情的经过
Miss Durrells, I heard what happened.
我无法压抑我的愤怒
I am beside myself with outrage.
哪个比较重要...
Which is your priority ...
你的顽皮儿子
your naughty son
还是那个被不公平逮捕的杀妻犯
or the unjustly arrested wife-murderer?
他们已经把莱斯利放了
They have already let Leslie go.
斯皮罗斯 请别对任何人大吼大叫的
And, Spiro, please don't shout at anyone,
这只会让克斯提的处境更糟
it'll make things worse for Kosti.
德雷尔小姐是英国人
Miss Durrells is English.
他们非常值得信任
They are completely trustworthy.
非常值得信任
Completely trustworthy.
美丽又诱人的金鱼...
Beautiful tempting goldfish...
当然 他们肯定会归还的
which, of course, they will return.
好
Very well.
- 我会放了他 - 那就好
- I will let him go. - All right.
放了那囚犯
Release the prisoner.
晚一点 还有手续要办
Later. There is paperwork.
晚一点
Later?
Later.
晚一点 以后你要是想叫出租车
Later! You ever want a taxi,
我保证你会"晚一点"才叫得到
I'll make sure you get it later.
我们只需要去归还金鱼
So, we just need to go and give the goldfish back...
还有那份警局档案
and return the police file.
母亲非常担心 所以我翻译了它
Mother was getting really anxious so I translated it
但发现不是同一个克斯提
and it turns out I got the wrong Kosti.
挺容易的 但这是一份很可怕的档案
You know, easily done. It's a pretty gruesome file, actually,
我永远也当不了警察
I could never be a policeman.
我觉得你妈妈想走了
I think your mother wants to go.
你好 我们想见见伯爵夫人
Hello. We're here to see the countess.
我们把金鱼放下就逃吧
Let's leave the goldfish and make a run for it.
这不是金鱼的问题 这事关诚信
It's not about fish, it's about honesty.
除了对不起和谢谢
Don't say anything except
什么也别说 然后我们就走
sorry and thank you, and then we'll leave.
拉里是伯恩茅斯最差的地产经纪人
Larry was the worst estate agent in Bournemouth.
他得过一个奖 但奖杯太重了没办法带到这里
He won a prize but it was too heavy to carry here.
莱斯利痴迷于枪 差点就射中了我们的邮差
Leslie was gun-mad and nearly shot our postman.
我还好 但是格里只对那些
I was fine, but Gerry here was only interested
四条腿或者有鳞片的东西感兴趣
in anything with four legs or scales,
所以才来偷金鱼
hence the goldfish.
我母亲很显然喝太多了
Mother was drinking too much, apparently.
所以才把我们带到科孚
So that's why she brought us all to Corfu.
- 说说你自己吧 - 请原谅我女儿
- But tell us about yourself. - I must apologise for my daughter.
你就像一缕清风
Well, you're a breath of fresh air.
过奖了
Oh, you're so sweet.
丹尼斯绞尽脑汁来逗我开心
Dennis tries his best to entertain me
但好久前他已经没有办法了
but he ran out of ideas some time ago.
- 有人觉得我有点笨 - 我也是
- I'm told I can be a bit dim. - Me too.
- 西奥 - 你好呀 格里
- Theo! - Hello, Gerry!
- 你手里拿着什么 - 伯爵夫人送的礼物
- What have you got there? - A gift from the countess.
- 旅途怎么样 - 会议很有趣
- How was your trip? - Oh, yes, it was a fascinating conference.
一个瑞士的代表认为
A Swiss delegate tried to argue
软体动物是环节动物的后裔
that molluscs were descended from annelids,
但有些人认为正好相反
rather than the other way round,
大家差点就打起来了
which almost led to fisticuffs.
我可以想象得出来
I can imagine.
我们很想你 西奥
Oh, we've missed you, Theo.
马戈 格里 能给我们泡杯茶吗
Margo, Gerry, will you go and make us tea?
西奥 我有工作了
Oh, Theo, I've got a job,
当马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人的女伴
as lady's companion to Countess Mavrodaki.
我觉得马戈这份工作能稳定下来
Yes, I think Margo is going to be a survivor.
西奥 你消息很灵通
Theo, you know everything.
你有听说过一桩案子 一桩谋杀案
Have you heard of a case, a murder case,
涉案的是克斯提·帕帕多珀洛普洛斯
involving a Kosti Papadopolopoulos?
- 潘欧帕罗斯吗 - 潘欧帕罗斯
- Panoupolos? - Panoupolos.
我记得的是他妻子有外遇
As I remember it, his wife had an affair.
克斯提喝了酒 在一阵疯狂和愤怒之下
Kostis drank and, in a moment of madness and passion,
他把他妻子打倒在地 撞到头部然后死了
he knocked her over, she hit her head and died.
这才是我们的克斯提
So that's our Kosti.
谢谢你 西奥
Thank you, Theo.
西奥 我完成了我的第一部大作
Theo. I've finished my first major work.
太好了
Excellent!
这是一部天才之作吗 当然是的
Is it a work of genius? Yes, it is.
- 谁想听听我的作品 - 不
- Who wants to hear my writing? - No,
- 这太没礼貌了 - 我选择死亡
- too rude. - I'd rather die.
太好了 西奥想听
Good, Theo does.
高贵的紫色映在黄昏的天空
Proudly purple in the gloaming,
突如其来一阵刺痛的悲伤
a sharp displacement of sad air
他隐隐感觉到
made him aware obliquely of
左侧的运动 随着地球在持续地...
movement to his left flank as the Earth continued...
你妻子的事情我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your wife.
我知道那是个意外 很抱歉我没有相信你
I know it was an accident and... I'm sorry I didn't trust you.
我仍然深爱她
I love her still.
我心里每时每刻都在流泪
Inside I cry... all the time,
泪水像河流一样
like a river.
我也曾有丈夫
I had a husband and er...
他也死了 我明白你的感受
and he died too, so I understand how you feel.
我没有杀他 但是...
I mean, I didn't kill him but...
抱歉
Sorry.